# Nina Baliga

422 EARL ST ALEXANDRIA, VA 22314

EMAIL ninabaliga@gmail.com TEL 703.220.0704 WEBSITE http://ninabaliga.squarespace.com TWITTER @nbaliga1

## Profile

User Experience Designer and Digital Strategist with extensive experience in digital marketing, user research, and cross-platform website/mobile development. Proficient in all steps of user experience design. Critical thinker, driven, highly collaborative, and focused with a background in Project Management. Experienced in developing and implementing local, state and national programs for major organizations by approaching problems through an empathic lens.

## Skills

## Coding:

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript

## **UX/Design Tools:**

- · Adobe Illustrator
- · OmniGraffle Professional
- Axure RP
- InVision
- Flinto

## Content Management Systems:

- WordPress
- · Expression Engine
- Salsa

## **Project Management Tools:**

- Merlin
- Basecamp

#### Other Tools:

- Word
- Excel
- PowerPoint
- Keynote
- Pages
- Numbers

## Experience

## FREELANCE DIGITAL STRATEGIST & USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER - AUGUST 2013 - JUNE 2014 (WASHINGTON, DC)

Conducted competitive analysis and provided information architecture recommendations to Congressman for his 2014 re-election campaign. Built a working prototype of an antiques inventory management and sales mobile application using client-provided design specifications document

#### ACCOUNT SUPERVISOR - RTC (A WUNDERMAN GROUP) - MAY 2011 - AUGUST 2013 (WASHINGTON, DC)

Lead UX, design, project management, digital strategy and development team to build web and mobile sites for major pharmaceutical company. Compiled user research, conducted competitive analysis, and reviewed federal regulations to create overall web experience for physicians seeking medical samples and savings materials. Built multiple versions (desktop, mobile and responsive) to meet changing times and client needs.

#### SENIOR ACCOUNT MANAGER - MAVERICK DIGITAL - FEBRUARY 2010 - MARCH 2011 (NEW YORK CITY, NY)

Developed website architecture, design, and functionality based on client needs and resources to relaunch fully interactive and dynamic websites. Proposed and executed holistic digital strategies including social and paid search leveraging Google Analytics and market research to bring clients into modern marketing methods. Worked closely with designers and developers to ensure all products were meeting UX specifications, and ensure client satisfaction.

## DIRECTOR OF DEVELOPMENT & COMMUNICATIONS - EREF - OCTOBER 2009 - FEBRUARY 2010 (ALEXANDRIA, VA)

Lead all communications work to build organization's new website and build an internal database to leverage online communications, including e-mail newsletters, donation management, and listserv maintenance.

## DEVELOPMENT & COMMUNICATIONS MANAGER - NATIONAL CAPACO - FEBRUARY 2007 - OCTOBER 2009 (WASHINGTON, DC)

Incorporated Web 2.0 technologies including building a new website, social networking site, and blog to increase visibility and increase stakeholder engagement. Conducted market research and user research to enhance messaging and proposed new branding strategy for nascent non-profit. Oversaw all communications efforts including hiring and coordinating of communications firms and development of communications materials.

CAMPAIGN STRATEGIST/RESEARCHER - SEIU LOCAL 11 - JAN 2005 - SEPT 2006 (MIAMI BEACH, FL)

CAMPAIGN DIRECTOR - AMERICA COMING TOGETHER (ACT) - JUNE 2004 - NOVEMBER 2004 (MIAMI, FL)

CLEAN WATER ADVOCATE - FLORIDA PIRG - AUGUST 2002 - APRIL 2004 (TALLAHASSEE, FL)

## Education

**User Experience Design Immersive -** *General Assembly DC* - Graduate August 2014 10 Week, Full-Time, Intensive Course Crafted for UX Design Careers

Masters in Business Administration – University of Florida - Graduated April 2008

Bachelor of Arts, Sociology, Environmental Science - New York University - Graduated May 2002

#### Service

CO-ORGANIZER - CODE FOR NOVA BRIGADE - JUNE 2013 - PRESENT

Lead all organizing efforts for the National Day of Civic Hacking (May 2014), and currently building Designer and UXer participation in the group. Key point of contact between local governments and other organizations.

LEAD PARTNER ORGANIZATION IDENTIFIER - DESIGN THINKING DC (SUMMER OF DESIGN) - JUNE 2014 - PRESENT

COMMISSION MEMBER - ALEXANDRIA COMMISSION ON INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY - NOVEMBER 2009 - PRESENT